<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hello!👋 I am Devashree on Devashree Madhugiri</title>
    <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hello!👋 I am Devashree on Devashree Madhugiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classification and Regression using AutoKeras 🤖️💻</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-24/</guid>
      <description>AutoML assist in automating all time consuming tasks in machine learning projects. Tasks like setting up the model, data preprocessing, pipeline creation and more can be automated with minimal amount of code. There are several AutoML tools available which aim to speed up the ML processes. In this article, I share a tutorial on classification and regression task using an AutoML tool &amp;lsquo;AutoKeras&amp;rsquo;.
This guide has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get to Know Apache Flume from Scratch!🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-23/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Apache Flume is a part of the Hadoop ecosystem,designed to handle log and event data. It is an excellent data ingestion tool for a high volume of event-based data, especially unstructured data, into Hadoop. Apache Flume is an excellent data ingestion tool fit for aggregating, storing, and analyzing the data with Hadoop. In this beginner-friendly article, I share the basics of Apache Flume including its need and architecture, some important features, types of data flow, the pros and cons of Apache Flume, when to choose Apache Flume and a few real-world applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Python Libraries for Time-Series Analysis ⏰🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-22/</guid>
      <description>Time-Series analysis is an intergral part of Predictive Analytics. This involves analyzing past data to understand the impacting factors as well as forecast the future events. Earlier there were challenges in analyzing such sequential data due to the complexity involved but now with the advancements in Machine learning, different tools are available to process big data faster. These open-source tools help to quickly uncover patterns and deviations from the normal readings using different Time-Series analysis techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive Data Visualization Using Bqplot 📈📊</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-21/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization is an essential aspect in Data Analytics. Several open-source Python libraries for Exploratory data analysis (EDA) allow us to uncover the hidden trends and patterns in a dataset for better business decision-making. In this context, adding interactivity to plots helps data science professionals to understand datasets better. Although D3.js is a well-known tool for building interactive data visualizations; but it is challenging to use due to the requirement of familiarity with JavaScript.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide to Sharding in Data Engineering for Beginners 🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>Data sharding is an important concept in big data. With the increasing use of IT technologies, the amount of data generated is overwhelming. Data-driven decision-making has become popular in the recent past as companies tend to leverage the information hidden in big data to drive business decisions. However, this data cannot be stored entirely in a single database. To efficiently handle such a vast data, sharding is required. In this guide, I share the basics of sharding, its various facets and need for sharding along with its pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Augmentation Using 3 Python Libraries✨🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-19/</guid>
      <description>Image Augmentation helps to create additional data from the existing dataset. CNNs can be trained better with additional data for image classification tasks. There are several open-source Python packages for image data augmentation. In this article, I explore some commonly used image augmentation techniques using 3 Python libraries - Imgaug, Albumentations and Solt.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Understand Data Augmentation Using AugLy!🖼️💻</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-18/</guid>
      <description>Data Augmentation allows to extend the existing actual data. Deep Learning models can benefit from this process. Image, Audio, Video and Text formats can be augmented using open-source Python libraries. In this article, I share different image augmentation techniques using AugLy, an augmentation library from Facebook.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing Deep Learning Models with Visualkeras 🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-17/</guid>
      <description>Deep Neural Networks consists of multiple hidden layers. Although it is possible to visualize the structure of the deep learning model in Keras as a flowchart, there are some Python libraries which allow graphical representation of the neural networks for presentation purposes. In this article, I explore one such visualizaion library called &amp;ldquo;Visualkeras&amp;rdquo; for plotting the structure of neural networks.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide on ggplot2 in R 🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-16/</guid>
      <description>ggplot2 is a popular data visualization library in R. In this guide, I explore the data visualization capabilities of ggplot2 and share code for plotting a few charts.
This guide has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya has won the prize for &amp;ldquo;top 3 Guides&amp;rdquo; (Editor&amp;rsquo;s choice). Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 Extensions to Power up your Jupyter Notebook 🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-15/</guid>
      <description>Jupyter Notebooks are well-known for Machine Learning and Deep Learning projects. They are quite easy to use for beginners. In this article, I share 11 extensions for boosting the performance of Jupyter Notebooks. These extensions come in handy for code formatting and organizing. These extensions can be installed using &amp;lsquo;nbextensions&amp;rsquo; package in Python.
This article has been published as a part of Data Science Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya and has won the first prize 🥇 in the article category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web scraping with PyScrappy 🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-14/</guid>
      <description>Finding good datasets for practice are challenging to find. Although, there are several types of datasets available online, but it is exciting to build a dataset using the web scraping technique. For this, one needs to have some experience in writing scraping code. However, there are some libraries which allow the users to scrape the required data from different websites with minimal code and no expertise. In this article, I explore one such web scraping library called &amp;ldquo;PyScrappy&amp;rdquo; and few of its different web scraping modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Sklearn: Accelerate your machine learning models with AutoML 🤖</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>AutoML automates the process of machine learning for challenging real-world problems. Multiple AutoML tools are available for building better machine learning models. These tools allow building of complex machine learning models with just a few lines of code.In this article, I explore AutoML library &amp;ldquo;Auto-Sklearn&amp;rdquo; for its model building and algorithm selection capabilities with classification and regression examples. Auto-Sklearn library is based on the popular sklearn library for machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Cloud Computing for Machine Learning Beginners ☁️💻</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-12/</guid>
      <description>Big data handling is a challenge with standard hardware when we work on machine learning or deep learning models. To address this issue, we can avail the benefits of cloud computing. There are different cloud services available for data science and machine learning. This comprehensive guide covers the basics of cloud computing for machine learning. It also provides information on selection of a suitable cloud services provider for building machine learning models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use Python To Analyse Fitness Tracker Market: Step By Step EDA 📈📊</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>Fitness wearables are a trend today. With various players in the market offering trackers and smartwatches for the fitness concious individuals, it is interesting to explore the wide array of products in this market based on their features, prices, reviews and ratings.In this project, we analyze the fitness trackers&#39; market in India using Python. First we scrape the required data and later visualize it to generate interesting insights about the current situation of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginner’s Guide to AutoML with an Easy AutoGluon Example ⚙️📋</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-10/</guid>
      <description>Most of the Machine Learning processes like data cleaning, formatting and organization, algorithm selection, model building and optimization, etc. are quite tedious and time consuming. Automating such processes allows data scientists more time to focus on interpreting the results and improving the models to solve real-world issues. This automation of ML processes is achieved by the use of AutoML tools. Through this blog, I share information on several AutoML tools available and explore one of the tools &amp;ldquo;AutoGluon&amp;rdquo; for classification and regression examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌳 How To Build A Treemap In 3 Ways Using Python 🌳</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Data visualizations enable us to display vital information in a dataset. With several categories, displaying information for comparison becomes a challenging task with regular bar charts. In such case, using Treemap is a convenient way to visualize nested hierarchical data.In this article, I share the basics of treemaps with their use cases. Further, I present three different ways to build treemaps in Python using open-source libraries - Matplotlib, Seaborn+Squarify, and Pygal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Visualization in Altair 📊</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>There are various EDA libraries available in Python. Seaborn is one such popular library which caters to all the data visualization requirements in an EDA. In this blog post, I explore Data Visualization using another powerful library &amp;lsquo;Altair&amp;rsquo; and compare it with Seaborn library on a plot-by-plot basis.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EDA challenge🏅</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/projects/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/projects/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>I created this Dashboard viz for an EDA contest held on Youtube.  Read more about the contest viz here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Machine Learning Models Better with Explainable AI 💻</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2021 11:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-2/</guid>
      <description>The inner workings of a Machine Learning model are challenging to understand. Explainable AI aims to create a transparency by explaining how the machine learning model arrived at the decision. There are few interesting Explainable AI libraries for Python that present these details within an interactive dashboard. In this blog article, I have explored the ExplainableDashboard library with a simple regression model. This article has been published on the &amp;lsquo;Towards Data Science&amp;rsquo; blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restaurant Food Delivery Time⌚</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/projects/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/projects/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>My contest entry- A Power BI Dashboard for a Food delivery time dataset with 11095 rows x 9 columns.  This Viz has been featured in the article by AnalyticsIndiaMag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Interactive Dashboard using Bokeh and Pandas 📈</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Dashboards are important to convey all the relevant information altogether. There are some interesting dashboarding libraries in Python. Bokeh is a powerful tool but the coding for visualization takes some effort for a newbie. Hence, in this blog post, I build a beginner-friendly dashboard step-by-step using &amp;lsquo;Bokeh-Pandas&amp;rsquo; - a Bokeh based tool with Front-end Pandas support.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Portfolio Website using Coding🎨💻</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/projects/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/projects/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>This personal portfolio website is a sample of my html &amp;amp; css coding skills.
 Hosted on GitHub. Demo here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better EDA with 3 Easy Python Libraries for Any Beginner🔮✨</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>EDA is a time consuming process and requires some experience when it comes to presenting the insights from a given dataset. It is quite likely that any beginner would get overwhelmed with the existing array of Data Visualization libraries. Hence, AutoEDA is a good solution when you need a quick overview of the chosen dataset. In this blog post, I have shared a beginner-friendly tutorial of 3 important AutoEDA libraries - PandasProfiling, Sweetviz and AutoViz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CNN for Image Classification on CIFAR-10 Dataset</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Image classification has a wide range of applications in different industries. Neural Networks are a better choice for image based problems. In this blog article, I explore the CIFAR-10 dataset using CNN with a step-by-step tutorial. This dataset contains 6000 images and 10 labeled categories and is good starter dataset for Deep Learning.
This article has been published on Medium. Read the full blog article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes Prediction With PyCaret 🔍</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>AutoML libraries automate the process of machine learning. PyCaret is an open source Python library for AutoML. In this article, I explore this library using the Pima Indian Diabetes dataset with a detailed tutorial.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stroke Prediction with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I share the details of how I built &amp;amp; evaluated a machine learning model for predicting stroke. The dataset used for this project is the Stroke Prediction Dataset from Kaggle and the model built predicts whether a patient is likely to get a stroke based on the input parameters like gender, age, various diseases, and smoking status.
This article has been published on Medium. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Heart Diseases with a Machine Learning model</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I build a machine learning model using different ML algorithms to predict whether the person is suffering from Heart Disease or not. The dataset used for this project is Heart Disease UCI from Kaggle.
This article has been published on Medium. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/contact/</guid>
      <description>   Platform URL     email: 📧 devashreesm@yahoo.com   LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/devashree-madhugiri   Twitter: https://twitter.com/dev_subhash21   kaggle: https://www.kaggle.com/devsubhash   Medium: https://devashree-madhugiri.medium.com/   Analytics Vidhya: https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/author/devashreesm/   GitHub: https://github.com/Devashree21     </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
