<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classification on Devashree Madhugiri</title>
    <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/tags/classification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classification on Devashree Madhugiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/tags/classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Auto-Sklearn: Accelerate your machine learning models with AutoML 🤖</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-13/</guid>
      <description>AutoML automates the process of machine learning for challenging real-world problems. Multiple AutoML tools are available for building better machine learning models. These tools allow building of complex machine learning models with just a few lines of code.In this article, I explore AutoML library &amp;ldquo;Auto-Sklearn&amp;rdquo; for its model building and algorithm selection capabilities with classification and regression examples. Auto-Sklearn library is based on the popular sklearn library for machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CNN for Image Classification on CIFAR-10 Dataset</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 11:15:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-5/</guid>
      <description>Image classification has a wide range of applications in different industries. Neural Networks are a better choice for image based problems. In this blog article, I explore the CIFAR-10 dataset using CNN with a step-by-step tutorial. This dataset contains 6000 images and 10 labeled categories and is good starter dataset for Deep Learning.
This article has been published on Medium. Read the full blog article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diabetes Prediction With PyCaret 🔍</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-6/</guid>
      <description>AutoML libraries automate the process of machine learning. PyCaret is an open source Python library for AutoML. In this article, I explore this library using the Pima Indian Diabetes dataset with a detailed tutorial.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stroke Prediction with Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-7/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I share the details of how I built &amp;amp; evaluated a machine learning model for predicting stroke. The dataset used for this project is the Stroke Prediction Dataset from Kaggle and the model built predicts whether a patient is likely to get a stroke based on the input parameters like gender, age, various diseases, and smoking status.
This article has been published on Medium. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Heart Diseases with a Machine Learning model</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-8/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I build a machine learning model using different ML algorithms to predict whether the person is suffering from Heart Disease or not. The dataset used for this project is Heart Disease UCI from Kaggle.
This article has been published on Medium. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
