<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NoSQL on Devashree Madhugiri</title>
    <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/tags/nosql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in NoSQL on Devashree Madhugiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/tags/nosql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with NoSQL Database Called HBase 💻</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-25/</guid>
      <description>Although Apache Hadoop is popular tool for handling big data but for real-time analytics, we require HBase. HBase is an open-source non-relational, scalable, distributed database written in Java. It is a part of the Hadoop ecosystem and runs on top of HDFS. Applications that require random read-write operations for big data tend to use HBase. This tool provides a set of powerful inbuilt APIs for pulling or pushing data. Further,we can integrate HBase with Apache Hadoop’s MapReduce for tasks such as indexing, analytics, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Guide to Sharding in Data Engineering for Beginners 🖥️</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-20/</guid>
      <description>Data sharding is an important concept in big data. With the increasing use of IT technologies, the amount of data generated is overwhelming. Data-driven decision-making has become popular in the recent past as companies tend to leverage the information hidden in big data to drive business decisions. However, this data cannot be stored entirely in a single database. To efficiently handle such a vast data, sharding is required. In this guide, I share the basics of sharding, its various facets and need for sharding along with its pros and cons.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
