<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EDA on Devashree Madhugiri</title>
    <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/tags/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EDA on Devashree Madhugiri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 11:25:05 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/tags/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How To Use Python To Analyse Fitness Tracker Market: Step By Step EDA 📈📊</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-11/</guid>
      <description>Fitness wearables are a trend today. With various players in the market offering trackers and smartwatches for the fitness concious individuals, it is interesting to explore the wide array of products in this market based on their features, prices, reviews and ratings.In this project, we analyze the fitness trackers&#39; market in India using Python. First we scrape the required data and later visualize it to generate interesting insights about the current situation of the market.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🌳 How To Build A Treemap In 3 Ways Using Python 🌳</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 11:25:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-9/</guid>
      <description>Data visualizations enable us to display vital information in a dataset. With several categories, displaying information for comparison becomes a challenging task with regular bar charts. In such case, using Treemap is a convenient way to visualize nested hierarchical data.In this article, I share the basics of treemaps with their use cases. Further, I present three different ways to build treemaps in Python using open-source libraries - Matplotlib, Seaborn+Squarify, and Pygal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Data Visualization in Altair 📊</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-1/</guid>
      <description>There are various EDA libraries available in Python. Seaborn is one such popular library which caters to all the data visualization requirements in an EDA. In this blog post, I explore Data Visualization using another powerful library &amp;lsquo;Altair&amp;rsquo; and compare it with Seaborn library on a plot-by-plot basis.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an Interactive Dashboard using Bokeh and Pandas 📈</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 11:13:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-3/</guid>
      <description>Dashboards are important to convey all the relevant information altogether. There are some interesting dashboarding libraries in Python. Bokeh is a powerful tool but the coding for visualization takes some effort for a newbie. Hence, in this blog post, I build a beginner-friendly dashboard step-by-step using &amp;lsquo;Bokeh-Pandas&amp;rsquo; - a Bokeh based tool with Front-end Pandas support.
This article has been published as a part of Blogathon on Analytics Vidhya. Read the full article here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better EDA with 3 Easy Python Libraries for Any Beginner🔮✨</title>
      <link>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 11:14:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://devashree21.github.io/devashree-madhugiri/post/chapter-4/</guid>
      <description>EDA is a time consuming process and requires some experience when it comes to presenting the insights from a given dataset. It is quite likely that any beginner would get overwhelmed with the existing array of Data Visualization libraries. Hence, AutoEDA is a good solution when you need a quick overview of the chosen dataset. In this blog post, I have shared a beginner-friendly tutorial of 3 important AutoEDA libraries - PandasProfiling, Sweetviz and AutoViz.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
